Hello everyone. Welcome back to today's another new tutorial topic. So today here I can create the null
values. Okay. So today we are going to explore the concept of the null values in the SQL and
perfectly understand the null values creating for what can you attribute that database. Okay.
So first of all, just simply understand defining from the SQL null values. So here the null is
the special value in the SQL that represents the actual some value unlike data. It's essential
for handling the null value correctly in that database query. Okay. So first of all, I can already
here define the new table for the employee stable. Okay. And next step here inserting the null
values. So now just let's start with the example inserting the null values into a table. Okay. So here
I can create for the table structure is a column used for the total fulfillment now here insert for
is the insert the sample data. So first of all here define for the employer ID one and next step here
I can just type the employee's first name. So here define for the first name juhan and next year insert
for the last name and also here I can insert for agent now define it is called the null value. Okay.
So now here it is for the department of the ID. Okay. So now you can see here perfectly
define for the employee ID and now just go here and just check the employee perfect and here
simply just inserting a new record with the employee stable with the column set to null and now
just here I can select an execute. You can see here the employee ID here is not defined.
So now just I can go for again. So now here I can just skip for this. Okay. So now here simply
just create for the employee ID and now just again for select an execute now. You can see this is completely
successful. I'm going for here just create for simply this the employee. Okay. So now just check.
So first of all here again execute now you can see here the line invalid column for the employee ID.
So just remove and just again try okay. So here insert for the ID up to and then select an execute
and there same statement for the first name or the okay. So here you can see I'm not yet perfectly
inserted the employee. So you can see here I can create for the employee name and just again check
and just perfectly type it is called the employee. Okay. So this an employee and they are
create this template ID. Okay. So this one perfect and create the command and now just try and
execute and you can see here perfectly the window is affected. So previously
did mistake inside the employees. So next I can go here. So now just check for the null value.
So open the other new query and new type for here just select
Mr prompt here the employee table. This is not so this is
this one now put the semicolon and first of all select can execute and you can see perfectly
defined and show the null value. Okay. So I hope you perfectly understand and next is to clear
just coding record the null value. So you can use the is null and not not operator to filter record
within the null or the not null value. So now just try. So first of all we are create for the
employees and next step here is the workflow. So just here I can type the wire and define
for the H column the null value. Okay. So now it is defined perfectly and when I just see
there can execute you can see here step or true for this statement for the H column is null. Okay.
So now here I can create here the report for the employee stable. The H column is not and the
query return the employee where edges are known for the null is specified. So next step here
creating for here is update for. So define here is the updating record to set the null values.
Okay. So you can update the existing record to set the null values for the specific column.
So first of all here I can just open for another new query and then here I can just
type and first of all I can create the updates. So define for the update statement and then
define the employee stable. And next step here I can set the H column is equal to define the null
value. Okay. And now here we create and use the wire clause to define the first name.
And it's equal to inside here the first name is suppose like the Johan and here I can use the
end operator and here I can here this is the last name. So define the last name is not perfectly
typed here. It is called the last name is equal to. So declare it is the last name. Okay.
So here updating the H column for the employee name for the Johan null and this can be used
when the information is no longer relevant or need to be removed. Okay. So here I can select
the all statement and then execute. Now you can see here perfectly one row affected. So now
just check. So remove this and here insert the semicolon and again select then now execute and
you can see here perfectly see the result. And here first I can use the Johan and
the age is perfectly null. So here in this session is completely done and perfectly used the
whole view of the null values in the SQL would some practical example. Okay. So I hope you
particularly found this tutorial helpful. So stay tuned for more SQL tips and tricks. So thank you
Thank you for watching, okay?